Early days self-driving car we build a machine to drive through the desert,
早些时候 我们建造了一台机器开车穿越沙漠
Stanley, for the Dawawine Challenge and the machine drove really nicely.
在 Dawawine Challenge 赛中 Stanley 表现很棒
Except every 40 miles or so,
大概每隔 40 英里
it would see a magic big obstacle in front of
它会看到前面出现一个神奇的巨大障碍
it and freak out and attempt to jump down a cliff.
它会被吓坏了 并试图跳下悬崖
It was very rare.
这非常罕见
It was every 40 miles. It was like every two or three hours.
每隔 40 英里 大约每隔两三小时
It was very hard to catch and we were flabbergasted like why all of a sudden,
这让我们摸不着头脑 惊呆了 为什么突然间
everything's going perfect, all of a sudden,
原本一切都很完美 结果突然间
dust of all would see this random massive obstacle.
就出现了这个随机的巨大障碍
It took me months of my own time to figure that out and fast forward, here is the answer.
花了我几个月的时间才搞清楚 中间过程就不啰嗦了 直接说结果吧
We had a laser scanning the terrain and to make
我们制作了一台激光扫描器 用于扫描地形
sure that when laser data overlapped over time,
并确保当激光数据随时间重叠时
that you could bounce up and down,
你会上下颠簸
that we wouldn't fall into a trap to compare laser data,
从而不会陷入比较不在同一个框架内的
that wasn't in the same cone of frame.
激光读数陷阱
We just said look, the less laser reading and some time elapsed.
我们只是说 激光读数少了 一段时间过去了
The more time elapsed, the less confident we are.
时间过去得越多 我们变得越不自信
It was actually a good rule so we could actually have
这实际上是一条很好的规则
a situation if data was acquired very successfully in time, very confident.
所以如果能非常成功地及时获得数据 我们会非常自信
We're telling between, we compared all data points, less confidence.
我们对比所有的数据点 自信心受损
Then, we imported this architecture to multiple computers and exporting,
然后 我们将这个架构导入到多台计算机并导出
we had to sync the clocks of those computers.
我们必须同步这些计算机的时间
In the syncing of clocks of those computers,
在这些计算机的时间同步中
time would occasionally go backwards.
时间偶尔会倒退
What that did to our confidences was catastrophic.
对我们的自信心造成灾难性的打击
It was, all of a sudden, instead of relaxing confidence over time,
这意味着 突然间 不是随着时间放松信心
tighten confidences to the level that could never see no obstacle.
而是要坚定不会看到障碍的信心
It was really a combination of clock being backwards, as far as syncing,
当时 时钟倒退 直到所有时钟同步
and the car bouncing up and down at
与此同时 汽车上下颠簸
the same time that would cause that catastrophic situation.
造成灾难
Now I, as a software engineer,
现在 作为一名软件工程师
I wouldn't have asked the question of these bizarre obstacles,
我就不会问关于这些怪异障碍的问题
does the clock go backwards?
时钟会后退吗
It took us forever to even look at the right number to understand
当时真的花费了我们大量的时间 研究正确的数字
that this backwards-going clock could actually cause the car to crash.
才搞明白这种时间倒退会造成汽车坠落
That is one of these examples of a really,
这个例子
really hard to find bug.
告诉我们 有时候 找到正确的故障原因很难